<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000144f81</Id>
    <Library_Id>26bd1a04-beed-4a66-917d-b6ab0a7d634c</Library_Id>
    <Title>Unvalidated Redirection</Title>
    <Category>Redirects and Forwards</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ASP.NET 4.0</Technology>
    <Type>Landing Page</Type>
    <DirectLink>Unvalidated Redirection</DirectLink>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="WikiText">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Description==

Unvalidated redirection vulnerabilities allow attackers to craft URLs that appear to lead to a legitimate site, but actually lead to a malicious site. An attacker may be able to leverage this vulnerability to trick users into entering sensitive information into a malicious website while seemingly navigating within a trusted website.

==Countermeasures==

The following TeamMentor articles describe effective counter-measures against unvalidated redirection vulnerabilities:

* [[97c6549f-abb4-41fe-ac16-b394e4ac4b16|Don't Use Redirects Or Forwards If Possible]]
* [[e4f51a77-5401-4aec-8c64-4198b2718b8d|Calculate Destinations of Redirects And Forwards Without User Input]]
* [[2869a8f0-93b8-4689-b531-d59367988a33|Use Mapping Values When Redirecting on User Input]]
* [[52982908-b692-41bc-afb1-8663e399c51c|Validate Destinations of Redirects And Forwards]]

==Checklists==

The following checklist items can help make sure that effective counter-measures against unvalidated redirection vulnerabilities have been implemented:

* [[9d028dc7-5faf-48d6-b445-2afed87b8394|Redirects And Forwards Are Not Used Unless Necessary]]
* [[ec9ba67e-9ff1-41b2-a346-1ca4b30a3479|Destinations of Redirects And Forwards Are Calculated Without User Input]]
* [[13912b44-0b4e-4792-a649-ee6bc16a3ede|Mapping Values Are Used for Redirects And Forwards]]
* [[ec9ba67e-9ff1-41b2-a346-1ca4b30a3479|Destinations of Redirects And Forwards Are Validated]]

==Additional Resources==

* For more information about unvalidated redirection, please see https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10_2010-A10-Unvalidated_Redirects_and_Forwards]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>