<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>21ab4ec0-04fb-49c8-bb1f-03fea9ac28b0</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000000b0d98,96d8cd55-3e74-4e26-a1b7-62189556df0c,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>26bd1a04-beed-4a66-917d-b6ab0a7d634c</Library_Id>
    <Title>Code Injection</Title>
    <Category>Dangerous APIs</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ASP.NET 4.0</Technology>
    <Type>Landing Page</Type>
    <DirectLink>Code Injection</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Description==

Scripting languages often have functions, such as eval(), that allow interpreting a string or a file as a part of the application. The danger of using these functions is that under certain conditions an attacker may be able to supply malicious code and it will be executed as a part of the application. This gives the attacker full control of the application. Code injection vulnerabilities affect all scripting languages, but typically occur in web applications written in PHP. To prevent code injection vulnerabilities, validate all input and avoid using dangerous functions. To check your application for code injection, find all the calls to dangerous functions and verify that data passed to them is sufficiently validated.

==Impact==

An attacker gains full control of the application and the ability to use any operating system functions that are available to the scripting environment. Code injection is one of the most dangerous vulnerability types, if not the most dangerous. On top of being extremely powerful, code injection vulnerabilities are typically easy to exploit, especially in web applications. 

==Countermeasures==

Validate all input:
* [[3de41277-0cc1-4ebc-8dd7-e96d161aa0ef|Validate All Input]]
* [[e59923e7-c2fb-4a75-8db7-a9a91e869f74|Validate Input for Length, Range, Format, And Type]]

Avoid using dangerous APIs:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000302a8f|Avoid Using Reflection]]

==Checklists==

All input is validated:
* [[a210fcb7-f142-4c2e-844a-c43e0859f90d|All Input Is Validated]]
* [[0e71dd64-87d1-4cf5-9569-ea320f209977|Input Is Validated for Length, Range, Format, And Type]]

Dangerous APIs are avoided:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-00000012cfad|Reflection Is Avoided]]

==Additional Resources==

* For more information about Code Injection, see http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Code_injection
* For more information about Code Injection, see https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Code_Injection]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>