<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>f9a980ca-a3f6-45b1-8b48-1e28048e4e95</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000007a1206,ea00a8ee-1248-42b5-9954-439a93fb14d8,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>26bd1a04-beed-4a66-917d-b6ab0a7d634c</Library_Id>
    <Title>Command Injection</Title>
    <Category>Dangerous APIs</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ASP.NET 4.0</Technology>
    <Type>Landing Page</Type>
    <DirectLink>Command Injection</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Description==

Applications often execute external commands as a part of their functionality. If the attacker is able to manipulate the choice of external commands or their parameters, the attacker may be able to use this functionality to execute arbitrary commands. If an attacker is able to execute arbitrary commands, he is typically able to take over the application and possibly take over the entire system. All applications that use external applications are affected by command injection vulnerabilities. Web applications are especially at risk, because they are exposed to the Internet. To prevent command injection vulnerabilities, validate all input, use parameterized APIs to execute external commands if such APIs are available, and avoid using external commands if possible. To check for this flaw, find all code that executes external applications and make sure that it does not use unvalidated input.

==Impact==

Command injection allows an attacker to execute arbitrary commands. Using this vulnerability an attacker can take full control of the application. If the attacker is able to leverage additional vulnerabilities or the server is not configured properly, this vulnerability may allow the attacker to take full control of the server. A command injection vulnerability acts as a virtual backdoor for an attacker to use the application and the server for his purposes. Any data that may be stored by or accessed by the application can also be compromised as a result of command injection.


==Countermeasures==

Validate all input:
* [[3de41277-0cc1-4ebc-8dd7-e96d161aa0ef|Validate All Input]]
* [[e59923e7-c2fb-4a75-8db7-a9a91e869f74|Validate Input for Length, Range, Format, And Type]]

Use parameterized APIs:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-00000077e119|Use Parameterized APIs to Launch External Processes]]
* [[784d6ed5-5c29-4634-a3dd-8f42f33dba6e|Securely Execute a New Process]]

Avoid using external commands:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000187386|Avoid Using External Commands]]

==Checklists==

All input is validated:
* [[a210fcb7-f142-4c2e-844a-c43e0859f90d|All Input Is Validated]]
* [[0e71dd64-87d1-4cf5-9569-ea320f209977|Input Is Validated for Length, Range, Format, And Type]]

Parameterized APIs are used:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000005ad6ba|Parameterized APIs Are Used to Launch External Processes]]

External commands are avoided:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000003f9f92|External Commands Are Avoided]]

==Additional Resources==

* For more information about command injection, please see https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Command_Injection 
* For more information about command injection, please see http://software.e-articles.info/Command-Injection]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>