<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>0cd0323c-88b1-4b26-87b8-f0e6bc30a47e</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000861d97,0cd0323c-88b1-4b26-87b8-f0e6bc30a47e,efc23862-ac67-48f2-b548-f004124fa738,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Sensitive Cookie in HTTPS Session without Secure Attribute</Title>
    <Category>Session Management</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>Java</Technology>
    <Type>Vulnerability</Type>
    <DirectLink>Sensitive Cookie in HTTPS Session without Secure Attribute</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[=Description

When a Cookie has the Secure flag set, that cookie will not be sent over a non-encrypted connection. If the Secure attribute is not set on a sensitive cookie, the cookie may be sent in plaintext and an attacker may intercept it. If an attacker is able to intercept a session cookie, he can impersonate an authenticated user. This vulnerability affects web applications that use authentication. 

=Impact

Sending a sensitive cookie in plaintext creates a risk that an eavesdropping attacker may intercept it. Once the attacker has intercepted a session cookie, he can use it to hijack the user's session. Hijacking the user's session allows the attacker to impersonate that user. If the attacker hijacks an administrator's session, the attacker may take full control of the application. 

=Countermeasures

To prevent this problem, set Secure and HTTP-Only flags on all sensitive cookies and send session cookies over HTTPS. 

Set Secure and HTTP-Only flags on all sensitive cookies:
* [[9b7e6e63-c37c-403b-a2f5-60b1e1abbb0b|Set the Secure And HTTPOnly Flags on All Sensitive Cookies]]

Send session cookies only over HTTPS:
* [[6012e717-6ba6-4380-8ca8-2f0b7c69d717|Protect Session Cookies]]

=Application Check

To check for adequate protection against this vulnerability, find all code that stores session cookies to ensure that it sets the Secure flag, and ensure that session cookies are sent over HTTPS. 

Secure and HTTP-Only flags are set on all sensitive cookies:
* [[d8922a46-a943-4ae0-b8af-b88eb01d6997|The Secure And HTTPOnly Flags Are Set on All Sensitive Cookies]]

Session cookies are sent only over HTTPS:
* [[59132a30-2bae-45e9-9d85-8de26441be29|Session Cookies Are Protected]]

=Computer Based Training Links=

Use the following Computer Based Training courses for more background information about this type of vulnerabilities.

==OWASP Top Threats & Mitigations==

This course examines in depth the vulnerabilities, threats, and mitigations described in the OWASP Top 10 2013. Upon completion of this class, participants will be able to identify and mitigate the greatest threats that web application developers face, including: Injection, Broken Authentication and Session Management, Cross-Site Scripting (XSS), Insecure Direct Object References, Security Misconfiguration, Sensitive Data Exposure, Missing Function Level Access Control, Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF), Using Components with Known Vulnerabilities, and Unvalidated Redirects and Forwards.

[[https://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/139631|DES 221 OWASP Top Threats & Mitigations]]

//Valid login credentials and enrollment in the course itself are required to access Team Professor content. If you need login credentials, please contact support@securityinnovation.com for help.//

=Additional Resources

* For more information about this vulnerability type, see http://minsky.gsi.dit.upm.es/semanticwiki/index.php/Sensitive_Cookie_in_HTTPS_Session_Without_%27Secure%27_Attribute]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>