<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>1a7d87d3-eee8-4f1c-ab46-7aec1b5479fb</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000008e7f60,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Unchecked Error Condition</Title>
    <Category>Error Handling</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>Java</Technology>
    <Type>Vulnerability</Type>
    <DirectLink>Unchecked Error Condition</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Description==

Unchecked error conditions may allow attacks to go unnoticed. Checking error conditions helps the application to determine if something out of the ordinary is happening and to log that information. Log information helps administrators determine when an attack is taking place and provides information about the attack. Unchecked error condition flaws may occur in any type of application. 

==Impact==

Unchecked error conditions may result in other, more serious vulnerabilities. An unchecked error condition may not actually give any advantage to the attacker. However, if the application contains a lot of code that may produce unchecked errors, that creates a fertile field for the attacker to look for vulnerabilities. 

=Countermeasures

To prevent unchecked error conditions, use structured exception handling, use a global exception handler for unhandled exceptions, and log error information. 

Use structured exception handling:
* [[fceefe0c-900a-4c29-9c2e-ee662aa9e1f1|Use Structured Exception Handling]]

Use a global exception handler:
* [[3e815c74-4d57-4c1b-8446-750b319ea046|Use a Global Exception Handler for Unhandled Exceptions]]

Log error information:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000340de3|Log Error Information]]

=Application Check

To check for adequate protection against this vulnerability, verify that structured exception handling is used, a global exception handler is used, and error information is logged. 

Structured exception handling is used:
* [[2739df30-b3da-417e-8856-2201a2b2a17a|Structured Exception Handling Is Used]]

A global exception handler is used:
* [[c88e1b49-357d-4202-aafc-86ce0de485bd|A Global Exception Handler Is Used for Unhandled Exceptions]]

Error information is logged:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-00000078ce47|Error Information Is Logged]]

=Computer Based Training Links=

Use the following Computer Based Training course(s) for more background information about this type of vulnerabilities.

==Creating Secure Code – JRE Foundations==

In this course, you will learn to recognize and remediate common Java Web software security vulnerabilities.  This course has three modules, which introduce you to these vulnerabilities and help you to identify and remediate them.

[[http://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/127615|COD 211 Creating Secure Code – JRE Foundations]]

==Creating Secure J2EE Code==

This course introduces and explains the precautionary measures you can use to avoid Web software security vulnerabilities, such as data leakage attacks, client/server protocol manipulation, injection attacks, and exploiting authentication.  At the end of this course, you will have learned about time-tested defensive coding principles and how to use them to increase the security of your application, and prevent common security vulnerabilities.

[[http://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/127619|COD 313 Creating Secure J2EE Code]]

//Valid login credentials and enrollment in the course itself are required to access Team Professor content. If you need login credentials, please contact support@securityinnovation.com for help.//

=Additional Resources

* For the CWE page about this vulnerability type, see http://www.cvedetails.com/cwe-details/391/Unchecked-Error-Condition.html]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>