<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>418cfb77-5d0a-4fd9-9825-1732cf40070d</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000018af4,418cfb77-5d0a-4fd9-9825-1732cf40070d,f0783d6f-c328-44b6-baaa-d7020c8a9acd,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>LDAP Injection</Title>
    <Category>Input and Data Validation</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>Java</Technology>
    <Type>Vulnerability</Type>
    <DirectLink>LDAP Injection</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[==Description==

Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP) is a widely used protocol for accessing directory services. Directories provide a set of attributes about people that are organized in a hierarchical manner.  LDAP Injection is a technique to exploit applications that use input from users to query an LDAP directory. LDAP injection has the potential to view, modify, or remove personal information about anyone in the directory. LDAP Injection applies to all applications that use LDAP. 

==Impact==

LDAP injection allows an attacker to access and/or modify restricted data in the LDAP database. The attacker may leverage this vulnerability to view personal information of users in the database. The attacker may also leverage this vulnerability to give himself administrative privileges or to take over another account. Once the attacker has administrative privileges, he usually has full control of the application.

==Countermeasures==

To prevent LDAP injection, validate all input and use parameterized APIs if they are available. 

Validate all input:
* [[b531d29c-86f7-4812-90ce-5f3f0f780aba|Validate Input from All Sources]]
* [[c98695c5-cf02-44a1-96bf-1f8046b8ad9d|Validate Input for Length, Range, Format, And Type]]
* [[0f49430b-2abe-408f-b046-89fa739f5d53|Input Validation Using JSF]]
* [[18ac74df-602b-4a58-8998-52f638f3a045|Input Validation Using SpringMVC]]
* [[d124abb1-e230-43ef-8762-1caa0dbb89ca|Input Validation Using Struts 1]]
* [[2f917654-65a8-49c9-b000-c17f9765bf42|Input Validation Using Struts 2]]

=Application Check

To check for adequate protection against this vulnerability, find all code that queries directories and verify that data included in the queries is sufficiently validated. 

All input is validated:
* [[b531d29c-86f7-4812-90ce-5f3f0f780aba|Input from All Sources Is Validated]]
* [[61869793-2c10-40c0-b82a-babcc0312697|Input Is Validated for Length, Range, Format And Type]]

=Computer Based Training Links=

Use the following Computer Based Training course(s) for more background information about this type of vulnerabilities.

==PCI Best Practices for Developers==

Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards (PCI-DSS) provide minimum requirements for addressing the security of software systems handling credit card information. Addressing the requirements during the design and build stages of the development life cycle improves application security and simplifies compliance. This course will provide software developers with an in-depth understanding of application security issues within the PCI-DSS and best practices for addressing each requirement.

[[https://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/127647|COD 222 PCI Best Practices for Developers]]

==Creating Secure Application Architecture==

Software development is about creating functionality, features, and performance that meet user requirements. Secure system development requires you to think about what users want to do, what users should not be able to do, and then creating a solution. Users should not be able to access or tamper with resources that are not allocated to them.

[[https://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/127606|DES 311 Creating Secure Application Architecture]]

//Valid login credentials and enrollment in the course itself are required to access Team Professor content. If you need login credentials, please contact support@securityinnovation.com for help.//]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>