<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>baf9e37f-ae0c-4f38-99d4-1942aaefef44</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000755956,baf9e37f-ae0c-4f38-99d4-1942aaefef44,77328d7a-7f60-4e19-a4a9-bb86c143aac4,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Information Leak Through Cookies</Title>
    <Category>Session Management</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ASP.NET 4.0</Technology>
    <Type>Vulnerability</Type>
    <DirectLink>Information Leak Through Cookies</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[=Description

Cookies are used by web applications to store data in the browser. Cookies may be marked as persistent and stored for an extended period of time. An attacker may gain access to the drive that stores the cookies and recover sensitive data from them. The exact impact depends on the nature of the sensitive data in the cookies. This vulnerability applies to web applications that use cookies. 

=Impact

The exact impact of this vulnerability depends on the sensitive data stored in the cookies that the attacker has gained access to. Usually this is session data that keeps a user authenticated to an application. In that case, the attacker is able to impersonate the authenticated user. The ability to impersonate an authenticated user allows the attacker to carry out any actions that are available to that user within the application. That might be enough for the attacker, or he may use that access to leverage additional vulnerabilities for additional privileges. 

=Countermeasures

To prevent this vulnerability, don't store sensitive data in persistent cookies. 

Don't store sensitive data in persistent cookies:

* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000007cad1c|Do Not Store Sensitive Data in Persistent Cookies]]

=Application Check

To check for adequate protection against this vulnerability, find all code that stores cookies and ensure that sensitive data is not stored in persistent cookies. 

Sensitive data is not stored in persistent cookies:

* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-00000047e84e|Sensitive Data Is Not Stored in Persistent Cookies]]

=Computer Based Training Links=

Use the following Computer Based Training course(s) for more background information about this type of vulnerabilities.

==Creating Secure Code – .NET 4.0 Foundations==

This course describes .NET security features, including concepts such as Code Access Security (CAS) and .NET cryptographic technologies. It also provides secure coding best practices that will enable you to build more secure applications in .NET. 

[[https://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/127611|COD 215 Creating Secure Code – .NET 4.0 Foundations]]

==Creating Secure ASP.NET Code==

This in-depth course examines the development of secure Web applications in ASP.Net. It provides developers and testers with an overview of common Web application vulnerabilities and a set of nine best practices and techniques to follow in order to avoid them. Throughout the course, students are provided with interactive games and simulations designed to reinforce the secure design and coding concepts that were introduced.

[[https://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/127607|COD 311 Creating Secure ASP.NET Code]]

//Valid login credentials and enrollment in the course itself are required to access Team Professor content. If you need login credentials, please contact support@securityinnovation.com for help.//

=Additional Resources

* For the CWE page about information leaks through persistent cookies, see http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/539.html

* For more information about information leaks through persistent cookies, see http://minsky.gsi.dit.upm.es/semanticwiki/index.php/Information_Leak_Through_Persistent_Cookies
]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>