<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>ee22e5e0-0953-4276-b0e6-955becda5ee8</Id>
    <Id_History>00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000871a68,ee22e5e0-0953-4276-b0e6-955becda5ee8,9361aa69-190c-42c3-9b01-69d744d992f8,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Path Traversal</Title>
    <Category>Authorization</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>ASP.NET 4.0</Technology>
    <Type>Vulnerability</Type>
    <DirectLink>Path Traversal</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[=Description

Some applications allow the user to choose what files to access. Some of these applications don't validate the selected file path sufficiently. This path traversal vulnerability allows an attacker to access files outside of the locations authorized by the application. Path traversal vulnerabilities typically affect web applications. 

=Impact

Using path traversal, an attacker is able to access files outside of the scope allowed by the application. The attacker may then access sensitive operating system files, and application configuration files that include connection strings, application source code, and other sensitive data. The attacker will usually attempt to leverage information gathered using path traversal to take full control of the application or the application server.

=Countermeasures

To prevent this problem, canonicalize all file paths and name input, validate all input, and perform access control checks for all filesystem access.

Canonicalize all file path and name input:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000008dcc1f|Canonicalize All File Path and Name Input]]

Validate all input: 
* [[3de41277-0cc1-4ebc-8dd7-e96d161aa0ef|Validate All Input]]
* [[e59923e7-c2fb-4a75-8db7-a9a91e869f74|Validate Input for Length, Range, Format, And Type]]

Perform access control checks for all filesystem access:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000032b66|Perform Access Control Checks for Any Filesystem Access]]

=Application Check

To check for adequate protection against this vulnerability, ensure that all file path and name input is canonicalized, all input is validated, and access control checks are performed for all filesystem access.

All file path and name input is canonicalized:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-0000008acc7f|All File Path and Name Input Is Canonicalized]]

All input is validated:
* [[a210fcb7-f142-4c2e-844a-c43e0859f90d|All Input Is Validated]]
* [[0e71dd64-87d1-4cf5-9569-ea320f209977|Input Is Validated for Length, Range, Format, And Type]]

Access control checks are performed for all filesystem access:
* [[00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000032948|Access Control Checks Are Performed for All Filesystem Access]]

=Computer Based Training Links=

Use the following Computer Based Training course(s) for more background information about this type of vulnerabilities.

==Fundamentals of Application Security==

This two-part course is ideal for security and development practitioners that want to understand software security risk and seek specific implementation guidance on how to build and deploy more secure software applications.  It starts off describing why software security is critical and the risk that software vulnerabilities represent, and proceeds to lay the foundation for secure software development by presenting specific security controls and principles that development teams can implement immediately to reduce software risk. 

[[https://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/127105|AWA 101 Fundamentals of Application Security]]

==Creating Secure ASP.NET Code==

This in-depth course examines the development of secure Web applications in ASP.Net. It provides developers and testers with an overview of common Web application vulnerabilities and a set of nine best practices and techniques to follow in order to avoid them. Throughout the course, students are provided with interactive games and simulations designed to reinforce the secure design and coding concepts that were introduced.

[[https://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/127607|COD 311 Creating Secure ASP.NET Code]]

//Valid login credentials and enrollment in the course itself are required to access Team Professor content. If you need login credentials, please contact support@securityinnovation.com for help.//]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>