<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-484939964" Content_Hash="1907402930">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>2f79f252-08a8-4341-aa2f-4466a023a44e</Id>
    <Id_History>dc172f55-185d-4c34-996a-1e368662f3f7,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Exception Information Disclosure Attack</Title>
    <Category>Exception Management</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Attack</Type>
    <DirectLink>Exception Information Disclosure Attack</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>1</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies To
  </h1>
  <p>All applications.</p>
  <h1>Description</h1>
  <p>Attackers can use application error information to improve their ability to attack the application.</p>
  <p>Almost all methods calls in computer programs, provide some feedback to the calling method about the status of the operation. This feedback could be a function return value, an exception which was thrown by the called method, or an error string. Based on this feedback, an applications decides if it should tell the user about a significant result (usually success or failure). When an error occurs, some applications choose to echo the internal error messages to the user. Though this feature is helpful in debugging a problem, it could lead to an information disclosure issue. An attacker could use this technical information to gain a better understanding about the back-end processing of the product and craft more malicious attacks against it.</p>
  <h1>Impact</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>Disclosure of information about the internal functionality and resources of an application. </li>
    <li>Could lead to more serious attacks by the attacker.</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Vulnerabilities</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>Providing information returned by error exceptions to the user.</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Countermeasures</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <strong>Use generic error messages</strong>: Internal error messages should never be displayed to the user. Instead, for each error or a class of errors, generic error messages should be written and displayed to the user. These error messages should appropriately inform the user about a problem, but not divulge any extra information that could be used by an attacker. </li>
    <li>
      <strong>Handle all exceptions</strong>: General purpose exception handlers should be used to catch any exceptions which a developer may have overlooked.</li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Example</h1>
  <p>Consider this real world example where web browsers based on the Mozilla code base revealed too much information in the exception details returned to the web server from the web browser. <i><span id="summary_alias_container"><span id="short_desc_nonedit_display">Bugzilla Bug 267645: Page can obtain path to Mozilla installation or possibly profile by examining JavaScript exceptions</span></span></i> describes a situation where if a website called a method with bad-parameters an exception was thrown. This exception message is sent back to the website which calls the method and contains the following information:</p>
  <pre>[Exception... "Not enough arguments [nsIPromptService.alert]"  <br /> nsresult:"0x80570001 (NS_ERROR_XPC_NOT_ENOUGH_ARGS)"  <br /> location: "JS frame ::file:///C:/Program%20Files/mozilla.org/Mozilla/components/nsSidebar.js <br />::anonymous :: line 266"  data: no]</pre>
  <p>Here you will notice that the installation path of the application is revealed to the website. Other variations of this same problem were also found where the user profile path (which contains the user name) was also disclosed to the website. It may seem that divulging the installation path or profile path is not a serious issue, but an attacker can use this information towards crafting a targeted attack on the user.</p>
  <p>This problem has now been resolved by Mozilla and the following generic error is shown to the user when the same exception is triggered:</p>
  <pre>[object Error]</pre>
  <p>Even though this error message does not tell the user or the website exactly what went wrong, it does tell that an error occurred, providing an appropriate level of detail for the situation.</p>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>For more information on Bugzilla Bug 267645: <span id="summary_alias_container"><span id="short_desc_nonedit_display">Page can obtain path to Mozilla installation or possibly profile by examining JavaScript exceptions, see: <a href="https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=267645">https://bugzilla.mozilla.org/show_bug.cgi?id=267645</a><br /></span></span></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/7d83d845-cd2b-4067-bb4c-5fbb890b9c9e">Attack: Information Disclosure Attack</a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/74be8616-ad22-4d1d-a7fc-8ff3d145fc61">Guideline: Do Not Disclose Exception Details to the Client </a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/33a894ce-2061-4741-be92-1d063c9cf057">Guideline: Use a Global Exception Handler for Unhandled Exceptions </a>
    </li>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/b8a062a5-d2f0-48f4-a2ad-12e3606d7469">Guideline: Use Structured Exception Handling </a>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>