<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-576817280" Content_Hash="1861320446">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>577e90c9-8e44-4240-b00f-768316d63901</Id>
    <Id_History>e0ebf8be-838c-4762-8c44-0d90adf63aef,577e90c9-8e44-4240-b00f-768316d63901,bffb6ffe-79ba-4c40-b986-9268948ba153,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Account Lockout Attack</Title>
    <Category>Authentication</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Attack</Type>
    <DirectLink>Account Lockout Attack</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>2</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[=Applies To

All applications which perform authentication or use a third-party authentication module.

=Description

Normally, a lockout policy is used during authentication to prevent attackers from attempting a large number of passwords on a given account. However, in an account lockout attack, this security mechanism is used by an attacker to cause a denial of service condition. If the attacker can exhaust the invalid login attempt limit for a given account, that account may be locked out against the owner's wishes.

This attack is especially powerful if the attacker can guess a large number of usernames or account numbers for a scripted attack on many users.

=Impact

*Results in denial of service for the users whose accounts have been locked out.

=Vulnerabilities

*Weak implementation or configuration of the lockout policy. A weak policy could have any of the following characteristics:
        **Invalid login attempt limit too low.
        **Low or no timeout between login attempts.
        **No incremental timeout between unsuccessful login attempts.
*Valid username disclosure.
*This could be a result of an information disclosure vulnerability that lets an attacker distinguish between a non-existent username and a bad password.

=Countermeasures

*Configure the lockout policy to set the invalid login attempt limit to an acceptable limit, based on the security requirements of the application.
*Configure the lockout policy to increase the timeout after each failed login attempt. For example, require the user to wait two seconds after the first failed login attempt, four seconds after the *Use CAPTCHA values after a failed login attempt. If a user fails to log in properly, require them to authenticate themselves as not being a script by asking for a CAPTCHA response.
*Do not give away information which could lead to a distinction between a non-existent username and a bad password. To prevent this from happening, always display the same generic error message such as "Login information does not match, or if you have tried unsuccessfully to login more than X times, then your account has been locked" during the following events:
       **Invalid username
       **Invalid password for valid username
       **Valid username and valid password, but account locked out

It's important that any login timeouts be on a per-account basis. Often, attempts are made to lock out source IPs if a single IP has too many login failures to prevent an attacker from attacking a large number of accounts in parallel. However, this does not take into account the case where a large number of users are legitimately coming from a single source IP. This case is common today with the current proliferation of NAT devices. 

Instead, it is a better strategy to take steps to increase the required effort of the attacker. For example, require the client to hash the password a large number of times before submitting it. The hashed version is stored (safely encrypted) on the server, so the server requires no extra time to verify its correctness. However, the hashing process on the client is computationally expensive enough that an attacker will be unable to brute force multiple accounts on a single machine. Monitoring is also effective here: If an account stays in a locked state for too long and multiple failed login attempts recur to keep it that way, it should be brought to the attention of support personnel who can make a judgement call as to the appropriateness of more aggressive filtering, possibly after contacting the user.

=Additional Resources

    *For more information about CAPTCHA, see http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Captcha

=Related Items

*[[8482159c-5ec2-4b89-9c65-9af765030ff5|Attack: Information Disclosure Attack]]
*[[468c8d7a-ffc6-49ad-bef5-1886fd809a96|Attack: Denial of Service Attack]]
*[[49f1d246-0c79-48dd-90d0-39e52a17d8cc|Attack: Phishing Attack]]
*[[41ff6525-2cae-40a5-91e9-365d2d26feb9|Attack: Man in the Middle Attack]]]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>