<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1963468740" Content_Hash="-546693000">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>96a66ca5-91b1-4c5a-80eb-fd0da97713ae</Id>
    <Id_History>23b765dd-4de0-4374-8312-b6e0a1966c9f,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>92718d53-36b2-47bc-b6f5-e60994385f46</Library_Id>
    <Title>Social Engineering Attack</Title>
    <Category>Security Token Service</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Attack</Type>
    <DirectLink>Social Engineering Attack</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>1</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="Html">
    <Data><![CDATA[<h1>Applies To</h1>
  <p>Any system that stores, transmits, or processes sensitive data, or controls access to valuable resources.</p>
  <h1>Description</h1>
  <p>During a Social Engineering attack, an attacker relies on human interaction for the purpose of obtaining confidential information about a person or an organization, or in an attempt to gain unauthorized access to a system. The victim is usually tricked into performing actions that bypass security measures, or into revealing sensitive information. Some examples of social engineering attacks are:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <strong>Phishing</strong>: Sending out mass emails asking recipients to click on a link, and verify confidential information, such as their username, password, social security number, etc. The link leads them to a website that appears to belong to a legitimate organization, but is owned by the attacker instead. The victim then sends the sensitive information to the attacker who stores it on his server and redirects the user to the legitimate login page of the site he was spoofing. <li><strong>Phone phishing</strong>: Calling and posing as a legitimate organization or employee to request the victim's help to bypass a security mechanism such as a firewall or to request confidential/sensitive information from the user. <li><strong>Shoulder surfing</strong>: Watching while someone is entering username and password at the keyboard, or while someone is entering their PIN at an ATM <li><strong>Dumpster diving </strong>: Sifting through residential or commercial trash for confidential information such as passwords, credit cards, etc</li></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Impact</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <strong>Information Disclosure </strong>: An attacker may be able to recover information from a user directly or through other reconnaissance methods such as sifting through trash or watching as the user input sensitive information. <li><strong>Credential Disclosure</strong>: A victim may disclose credential information to an attacker inadvertently. <li><strong>Elevation of Privilege</strong>: An attacker may be able to gain access to systems or resources, which they should not have access to by convincing a legitimate user to help them circumvent access controls or to otherwise act on their behalf.</li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Vulnerabilities</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <strong>Lack of education</strong>: Users and employees must be educated to know that application or service providers will never ask for confidential or sensitive information. <li><strong>Inconsistent UI</strong>: If a user or employee is used to accepting invalid certificates, clicking on odd looking links, or giving sensitive information to IT staff or other employees they will be more likely to fall victim to a Social Engineering Attack. <li><strong>Improperly destroying physical data</strong>: All sensitive information, whether on paper or digital storage media, must be completely destroyed before being thrown away. </li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Countermeasures</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <strong>Education </strong>: Educate your employees and users to never divulge sensitive information and to hide sensitive information from third party onlookers. <li><strong>Consistent UI</strong>: Create consistent user interfaces so that your users can more easily recognize invalid/malicious behavior. <li><strong>Properly destroy all hard copy</strong>: Destroy data backups, paper hard copies, hard drives, and other media according to the necessary specification.</li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Additional Resources</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>Social Engineering: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_engineering_(computer_security">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_engineering_(computer_security</a>) <li>Examples of Social Engineering attacks and ways to prevent them: <a href="http://searchsecurity.techtarget.com/tip/1,289483,sid14_gci865450,00.html">http://searchsecurity.techtarget.com/tip/1,289483,sid14_gci865450,00.html</a><li>Paper/Data shreding: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paper_shredder">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paper_shredder</a></li></li></li>
  </ul>
  <h1>Related Items</h1>
  <ul>
    <li>
      <a href="/article/c8ae222b-ed2e-4621-a46b-3671f82f5a03">Attack: Phishing Attack</a>
      <li>
        <a href="/article/6a219806-df28-4c00-bc2d-c2ce4c721b7e">Attack: Trust Relationship Attack</a>
        <li>
          <a href="/article/d22c8d99-a690-4a68-bccf-5cb2894af160">Attack: Repudiation Attack</a>
          <li>
            <a href="/article/40188a30-1dab-4905-93ba-377068d670ca">Guideline: Verify the Application's Authenticity to the User </a>
          </li>
        </li>
      </li>
    </li>
  </ul>]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>