<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="-1283144909" Content_Hash="246396387">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>9d60faca-687b-4c69-91ba-f5712af0fd02</Id>
    <Id_History>110cc11a-5a28-4fc2-a269-4210069b8865,9d60faca-687b-4c69-91ba-f5712af0fd02,c73b76bf-f01d-4304-b44e-ae0e8a4d9ebf,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Server-Side Code Injection Attack</Title>
    <Category>Input and Data Validation</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Attack</Type>
    <DirectLink>Server-Side Code Injection Attack</DirectLink>
    <Tag />
    <Security_Demand />
    <Author />
    <Priority>1</Priority>
    <Status />
    <Source>SI</Source>
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="true" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[=Applies To

All web applications that process user-supplied input on the server.

=Description

In a server-side code injection attack, and attacker submits malicious input which gets executed on the server. This malicious input could be submitted in many different ways, including web form elements and URL parameters. Since the malicious input needs to be crafted and submitted in a manner that forces the back-end applications on the server to process the input, the attacker usually needs to gain an understanding of the back-end applications. Attackers can gain knowledge about the back-end system by using an information disclosure attack.

Depending on the type of back-end applications, the type of attacks vary. Some common server-side code injection attacks are:

    *SQL injection attack
    *Command injection attack
    *Buffer overflow attack

=Impact

    *Execution of malicious code on the server, which may threaten the confidentiality, integrity and availability of services and data.

=Vulnerabilities

    *Weak or no validation of user-supplied input.
    *Running with elevated privileges: Although this does not result in code execution, it does make the impact of an attack much worse.

=Countermeasures

    *Validate input: Validate user-supplied input for type, size, form and content before it is processed by the server.
    *Separate of control and data flow: Segregate user input from any context where control information is present, and maintain the separation.

=Example

Please refer to the examples presented in the Related Items linked below. 

=Related Items

    *[[b1757bda-0a0d-48e7-b101-3c4088e41878|Attack: SQL Injection Attack]]
    *[[8698cde2-0fdf-4676-a043-ae90e62f55b8|Attack: Command Injection Attack]]
    *[[36ce61ac-adcc-45a9-9910-95d477142c8b|Attack: Cross Site Scripting Attack]]
    *[[ae392dbb-fdb4-443f-9d17-78240b4acc95|Attack: XML Injection Attack]]
    *[[1508d763-03f1-4b43-bf8e-ad7cf8edebd7|Attack: Xpath-XQuery Attack]]
    *[[61f0d74e-d9b6-4e27-9e12-da65baff83fd|Attack: LDAP Injection Attack]]
    *[[e4a899ec-9301-4751-ae07-69a265336d8b|Attack: AJAX Injection Attack]]
    *[[a6fb7a4c-d169-491d-a392-ce9a7ccb5a1d|Attack: Format String Attack]]

]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>