<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>2674f188-5758-47f2-b0f1-c2286999d166</Id>
    <Id_History>2674f188-5758-47f2-b0f1-c2286999d166,0dba34ff-9af2-4807-a433-7d338672bcd6,</Id_History>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Integer Overflow</Title>
    <Category>Input and Data Validation</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology>C++</Technology>
    <Type>Vulnerability</Type>
    <DirectLink>Integer Overflow</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[=Description=
Integer overflows occur when the application tries to assign a number that is too large for the variable data type that it is being assigned to. Integer data types have a finite amount of possible values, which means that each integer variable has a minimum and a maximum value. Trying to assign a number to an integer variable that is greater than its maximum value results in an integer overflow. Trying to assign a number to an integer variable that is smaller than its minimum value results in an integer underflow. The minimum and maximum values for each data type are different for different platforms, but there are some generally agreed-upon conventions. 

The exact behavior of the application code when an integer overflow occurs depends on the platform. Most commonly, the value of the integer variable will "wrap-around". The "wrap-around" effect can be described as a dial spinning past its maximum value to start again at its lowest value. For example, advancing a clock by two hours from 9 o'clock will bring it to 11 o'clock; advancing that same clock by two more hours will bring it to 1 o'clock. 1 is a smaller integer value than 11, because the values "wrapped-around". 

The underlying cause of integer overflows is usually assigning the products of calculations with large numbers to integer variables and using untrusted data for numerical calculations. 

=Impact=
The impact of integer overflow vulnerabilities depends on many variables, but usually results in the application crashing, the attacker abusing business logic, and sometimes execution of arbitrary code. One of the most likely scenarios involving integer overflows is when an integer is being used as the index for a loop—if the attacker manipulates the index value, he can cause the loop to perform in an unexpected manner and crash the application. 

Execution of arbitrary code using integer overflows usually occurs when a vulnerable integer variable is used to control the amount of memory allocated for data. If the attacker can manipulate the amount of memory allocated and the data placed into that memory, he can usually execute arbitrary code with the privileges of the application. Such a vulnerability is actually a form of buffer overflow, but it relies on the integer overflow to be exploitable. In such cases, operating system and platform specific defenses against buffer overflows that are deployed on the target system might mitigate the vulnerability. However, generally speaking, integer overflow based buffer overflows result in arbitrary code execution and can be difficult to detect with code analysis.

=Countermeasures=
To prevent integer overflows, validate all input, and check results of calculations for maximum and minimum values before assigning them to integer variables.

* [[a8eb9762-08f6-4e61-afa7-23386cbca281|Validate All Input]]
* [[eeb8a6d5-2181-48fa-8b2a-3e44a532a50a|Validate Ranges of All Integer Values]]
* [[2f6f114a-7be0-4f92-8a45-23a6029dbcf1|Prevent Unsigned Integers from Wrapping]]

=Application Check=
To check for adequate protection against integer overflows, verify that all input is validated, and results of calculations are checked for maximum and minimum values before assigning them to integer variables.

* [[8d8c24b0-096b-43f4-9391-9b293313a0e8|All Input Is Validated]]
* [[4b60e560-1e2d-4284-bc67-b9a0edf1ff96|Integer Values Are Validated]]
* [[747fed1a-6444-4fe1-86f3-ff48bf344938|Unsigned Integers Don't Wrap]]

=Computer Based Training Links=

Use the following Computer Based Training courses for more background information about this type of vulnerabilities.

==Creating Secure Code – C/C++ Foundations==

This course will provide an overview of the threat modeling process and describe the ways to collect information for your application, build the activity-matrix and threat profile, and analyze risks.  It will also teach you the nine defensive coding principles and how to use these principles to prevent common security vulnerabilities.

[[https://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/127613|COD 212 Creating Secure Code – C/C++ Foundations]]

==Creating Secure C/C++ Code==

In this course, you will learn to detect common coding errors that lead to vulnerabilities. You will learn to effectively remediate the most common security vulnerabilities, and use the right tools to secure your code and detect security vulnerabilities early in the project lifestyle.

[[https://teamprofessor.absorbtraining.com/ninja/#/courses/course/127609|COD 312 Creating Secure C/C++ Code]]

//Valid login credentials and enrollment in the course itself are required to access Team Professor content. If you need login credentials, please contact support@securityinnovation.com for help.//
]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>