<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>79e3c551-71ae-4120-8542-a6f90823ede9</Id>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Insecure Randomness</Title>
    <Category>Cryptography</Category>
    <Phase>Implementation</Phase>
    <Technology> Any</Technology>
    <Type>Vulnerability</Type>
    <DirectLink>Insecure Randomness</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[=Description=
Insecure randomness vulnerabilities occur when a pseudo-random number generator with poor entropy is used for cryptography. With poor entropy, the results of the cryptographic algorithm being used become easier to predict, thus weakening the cryptography overall. 

It is important to distinguish between encryption and cryptography in general: Encryption is a subset of cryptography, and refers to scrambling stored data in a manner that can be reversed, whereas cryptography is a more general term that refers to using a certain type of  algorithm for a practical application. 

Insecure randomness issues affect all applications that use cryptographic algorithms that require random numbers for proper operation (which is virtually all of them). 

=Impact=
If a pseudo-random number generator with poor entropy is used, the cryptographic scheme can be broken in a short time. The exact impact depends on the cryptographic scheme being used and its purpose. One possible scenario is when a poor source of randomness is used to generate authentication keys - in this case an attacker will be able to generate unauthorized authentication keys. Another possible scenario is when a poor source of randomness is used as a part of an encryption scheme - in that case an attacker will be able to recover encrypted data.

=Countermeasures=
To prevent insecure randomness vulnerabilities, use a cryptographically strong pseudo-random number generator.

=Application Check=
To check for adequate protection against insecure randomness vulnerabilities, make sure that a cryptographically strong pseudo-random number generator is used.

=Specific Technologies=

* [[0a4a96d8-a365-4576-b2d2-b313c8753928|Java Insecure Randomness]]
* [[5cdbc019-536d-4c36-ad03-de11031a0f04|PHP Insecure Randomness]]]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>