<?xml version="1.0"?>
<TeamMentor_Article Metadata_Hash="0" Content_Hash="0">
  <Metadata>
    <Id>e98acf08-d551-41b4-8e61-8d4581752a57</Id>
    <Library_Id>be5273b1-d682-4361-99d9-6204f2d47eb7</Library_Id>
    <Title>Integer Overflow</Title>
    <Category />
    <Phase />
    <Technology />
    <Type />
    <DirectLink>Integer Overflow</DirectLink>
    <Author />
    <Priority />
    <Status />
  </Metadata>
  <Content Sanitized="false" DataType="wikitext">
    <Data><![CDATA[=Description=

An integer overflow occurs when an integer is incremented over the maximum value that the data type can hold. The resulting value depends on the compiler in use. ISO C99 defines the result of an integer overflow to be the assigned value modulo one more than the maximum integer size. This is also known as wrapping around zero.

Unlike buffer overflows, when an integer overflow occurs no memory other than that used by the integer is affected. However, it is easy for a programmer to assume that increasing the value of an integer will result in a larger integer. When the opposite happens unexpectedly, the program logic is altered. It is important to note that unless a check is added, the program has no way of knowing that the integer overflow happened and hence will continue with the assumption that the integer has the correct value. This is particularly a problem when a program is deciding how much memory to allocate for another variable. Common side effects are heap corruption causing the program to crash or a buffer overflow allowing arbitrary code execution.

=Impact=

Denial of Service: Erroneous and unexpected integer values from an overflow can cause the application to crash.

Data Corruption: If the result is used in a file read or write operation the application may read or write from the wrong place in disk or memory, resulting in corruption.

Remote Code Execution: Often remote code may be executed if the overflowed integer is used for memory management or indexing into a buffer.

=Countermeasures=

Arithmetic checking: Always check that the value of adding two positive integers is greater than either operand. Take extra care when performing arithmetic operations with values near the maximum of the data type.

Using a language or framework that does integer checking: Frameworks like .NET and java can be set to automatically check for integer overflows and underflows. (e.g., CheckForOverflowUnderflow in C#, RemoveIntegerChecks in VB.NET)

Input Validation: Validate the untrusted input for upper and lower limits

Verify Logic: Ensure that all integer logic will operate appropriately for the accepted limits, in all cases.

=Application Check=

]]></Data>
  </Content>
</TeamMentor_Article>